Register of the James A. Code Papers, 1923-1952
Hoover Institution Archives
James A. Code Papers,
1923-1952
72055
Code, James A., 1893-1972
2 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope, 1 medal case (1 linear foot)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, autobiography, reports, memoranda, military orders, citations, and printed matter, relating primarily to the operation of the U.S. Signal Corps, especially during World War II. Includes three Italian government documents relating to Benito Mussolini.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Mussolini, Benito, 1883-1945; United States. Army --Officers; United States. Army. Signal Corps; World War, 1939-1945; Italy; United States --Armed Forces
Biography
1893, January Born, San Francisco, California
1917 B.S., U.S. Military Academy
1920 M.S., Yale University
1942-1945 Major General, Assistant Chief Signal Officer
1945 Chief Signal Officer, European Theater (France)
1946 Chief Executive, Gary Group Companies
Scope and Content of Collection
James A. Code was also known as James A. Code, Jr.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1923-1952 (Box 1.)
  - A, B, C
  - Adams, A. F.
  - Allison, Major General James B.
  - Arnold, General H. H.
  - Behn, Sosthenes
  - Bickelhaupt, Brigadier General Carroll O.
  - Borremans, L. (Consul General of Belgium)
  - Cassady, P. M.
  - Clark, General Mark W.
  - Clay, General Lucius D.
  - D, E, F, G
  - Dobrski, J. A.
  - Eisenhower, General Dwight D.
  - Gary, Hunter L.
  - H, I, J
  - Hooper, Rear Admiral Stanley C.
  - Jewett, Frank B.
  - K, L, M, N
  - Leahy, Admiral William D.
  - Lenzner, Major General Emil
  - Mauborgne, Major General J. O.
  - Merlin, General Lucien L.
  - Miley, Major General W. M.
  - Mitchell, T. H.
  - Nicholls, Major General Leslie B.
  - O, P, Q, R
  - Olmstead, Major General Dawson
  - S, T, U, V, W, X, Y, Z
  - Sarnoff, David
  - Simpson, Major General C. H.
  - Sproul, Robert G.
  - Stimson, Henry L.
  - Warner, Harry M.
  - Zanuck, Darryl F.
  - Unidentified
- Writings
  - Holograph manuscript of autobiography
  - Typescript manuscript of autobiography
  - Published articles about the Signal Corps and communications (Box 2.)
  - Contribution to the U.S. Army in World War II: Signal Corps, The Outcome
- Biographical material
  - Who's Who entries and clippings
  - Military personal history
  - Personal service record
  - Civilian personal history
- Genealogy of Code family
- Scrapbook of letters of commendation and appreciation
- Letters of commendation and appreciation
- Military orders and awards
- Reports and memoranda relating to the operation of the Signal Corps, 1942-1944
- Miscellaneous printed matter
- Mementos and clippings
- Passport of Galeazzo Ciano dei Conti di Cortellazzo, 1935
- Authorization for establishment of a military award, signed by Benito Mussolini, April 21, 1943
- Election certificate for Benito Mussolini as deputy, 1934 (Oversize Map Case)
- Medal collection (21 pieces), includes: (Box 10v)
  - Distinguished Service Medal
  - Bronze Star Medal
  - Victory Medal, World War I
  - Pre-Pearl Harbor Medal, Campaign
  - Victory Medal, World War II
  - French Legion of Honor Officer
  - Belgium Order of the Crown, II Class
  - Commemorative Medal, Sons of American Revolution
  - Commemorative Medal, Sons of American Revolution
  - Two sets of Major General's stars
  - One set of Staff Corps insignia
  - Four medal ribbon bars